# MEGAN GILPIN

New York, New York T: (620) 481-1538 E: megangilpin@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/megan-gilpin Github: github.com/megangilpin Portfolio: megangilpin.com

## SUMMARY

Full Stack Engineer at the intersection of functionality and design with 10 years of experience developing creative consumer-focused products. Proven ability to oversee the strategy and growth of product lines. Highly skilled communicator and project manager who works well in fast-paced environments with tight deadlines. An underlying passion for innovation drove me to the pursuit of full stack web development through the Columbia Engineering Bootcamp.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

**LANGUAGES** - HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, React.js, MySQL, MongoDB, node.js, Express.js **APPLICATIONS** - Git, Heroku, Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Word, Excel, PowerPoint

## PROJECTS

#### ARRYVL - HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/MEGANGILPIN/FINITO | HTTPS://ARRYVL.HEROKUAPP.COM/

Full Stack MERN app that, with a click of a button, will track your location and share it with a friend. Arryvl maps your route as you head to your destination and informs those that care about you once you have arrived.

- Created with Mongo DB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Google Maps API, Twilio, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap.
- Core responsibilities included developing logo and initial prototype in Adobe XD, creating Google Map API calls, establishing back-end routes, built front-end to display user's journey to friend.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### ORIGINAL PENGUIN - NY, NY 2014 - Present

**DESIGNER** | OUTERWEAR / BOTTOMS / DENIM

- Oversee concept, design, and production of the global assortment; 450 skus per year in over 30 countries
- Maximized outerwear sourcing and design to improve margin by 10% within first year; consecutively achieved new maximum target margin per sku in all following years.
- Implemented bottom category relaunch, resulting in 83% growth in bottoms share of the total sales mix.
- Present concepts and designs to internal teams, including an annual global sales launch for an audience of over 200

#### KENNETH COLE - NY, NY 2009 - 2014

### ASSOCIATE DESIGNER | OUTERWEAR / SUIT SEPARATES

- Assisted in growing Reaction business from 150 Macy's doors to Macy's all doors.
- Managed CAD designer to ensure optimal productivity.
- Partnered with cross-functional teams to interpret selling results, sku plans, and design calendar to create product within given price ranges and time frames.

## ASSISTANT DESIGNER | OUTERWEAR / SUIT SEP. / KNITS / DENIM / WOVENS

- Communicated with overseas agents in over 5 countries throughout all stages of development and production.
- Created, organized, and maintained all technical packages.

## EDUCATION

#### FULL STACK BOOTCAMP CERTIFICATE / COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY - 2019

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

**BACHELOR OF FINE ARTS / ILLINOIS INSTITUTE OF ART - CHICAGO - 2009**